Register of the Trotsky collection, 1917-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- HARVARD UNIVERSITY SURVEY FILE, 1980 (Box 34-45)
  - Boggild, Bernard (Folder 42)
  - Boggild, Bernard, Mrs. (Folder 43)
  - Bokowski, A. (Folder 44)
  - Bosovich (Folder 45)
  - Bouwman (Folder 46)
  - Brenner, Anita (Folder 47)
  - Breton, Andre (Folder 48)
  - Brockway, Fenner (Folder 49)
  - Browne, Robert (Folder 50)
  - Buch, Vera (Folder 51)
  - Buchman, Alexander (Folder 52)
  - Bueno, Javier (Folder 53)
  - Bunk (Folder 54)
  - Burgess, Ernest Watson (Folder 55)
  - Burian, Vladimir (Folder 56)
  - Burnham, James (Folder 57)
  - Bynner, Witter (Folder 58)
  - Caby, Robert (Folder 59)
  - Calas, Nicolas (Folder 60)
  - Caldas Luna, Joaquin (Folder 61)
  - Caldis, Arist. (Folder 62)
  - Calverton, V. F. (Folder 63)
  - Cami (Folder 64)
  - Canfield, Cass (Folder 65)
  - Cannon, James P. (Box 35, Folder 1-2)
  - Carlo, Joseph (Folder 3)
  - Carlson, Peter (Folder 4)
  - Carter, Joseph (Folder 5)
  - Chakhotin (Folder 6)
  - The Challenge of Youth (Folder 7)
  - Chautemps, Camille (Folder 8)
  - Ch'en Tu-hsiu (Folder 9)
  - Christiana Bank (Oslo) (Folder 10)
  - Ciliga, Ante (Folder 11)
  - Claridad (Folder 12)
  - Claus, Otto (Folder 13)
  - Clay, Howard B. (Folder 14)
  - Cohn, Oscar (Folder 15)
  - Comisariado Ejidal "Lazaro Cardenas" (Folder 16)
  - Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials (Folder 17)
  - La Commune (Folder 18)
  - Communist League of Struggle (U.S.) (Folder 19)
  - Conway, M. G. (Folder 20)
  - Coolidge (Folder 21)
  - Corpening, M. M. (Folder 22)
  - Cortes Martinez, Pablo Emilio (Folder 23)
  - Corvin (Folder 24)
  - Cowles, David (Folder 25)
  - Craipeau, Yvan (Folder 26)
  - Le Crapouillot (Folder 27)
  - Cumhuriyet (Folder 28)
  - Curtis Brown Ltd. (Folder 29)
  - Curtiss, Charles (Folder 30)
  - Curtiss, Lillian (Folder 31)
  - Czech, Ludwig (Folder 32)
  - Czechoslovakia. Konzulat (Istanbul) (Folder 33)
  - Czechoslovakia. Ministerstvo Vnitra (Folder 34)
  - Dahl, Elizabeth (Folder 35)
  - Daily Herald (London) (Folder 36)
  - Daniel, Cuthbert (Folder 37)
  - Dauge, Walter (Folder 38)
  - Demby, F. L. (Folder 39)
  - De Silver, Margaret (Folder 40)
  - Despres, Leon Mathis (Folder 41)
  - Deutsch, Kurt (Folder 42)
  - Dewar, Hugo (Folder 43)
  - Dewey, John (Folder 44)
  - Diamond, Max (Folder 45)
  - Dobbs, Farrell (Folder 46)
  - Documentation Statistique et Economique (Folder 47)
  - Draper, Hal (Folder 48)
  - Driesten, Theo van (Folder 49)
  - Dunayevskaya, Raya (Folder 50)
  - Dunne, Vincent (Folder 51)
  - Duwell, Wilhelm (Folder 52)
  - Eastman, Max (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Enyclopaedia Britannica (Folder 2)
  - Epstein, Julius (Folder 3)
  - Ernst, Morris (Folder 4)
  - Espinoza, Enrique (Folder 5)
  - Estrina, Liliia (Folder 6)
  - Evang, Karl (Folder 7)
  - Fadiman, Clifton (Folder 8)
  - Faerge, Aage (Folder 9)
  - Farrar and Rinehart (Publishers) (Folder 10)
  - Farrell, James T. (Folder 11)
  - Feipel, Louis N. (Folder 12)
  - Feix, Anna (Folder 13)
  - Field, B. J. (Folder 14)
  - Field, Esther (Folder 15)
  - Fischer, K. (Folder 16)
  - Fischer, Paul (Folder 17)
  - Fischer, Ruth (Folder 18)
  - Fourth International. This and the following entries include material on the Fourth International's predecessors, the International Left Opposition and the International Communist League (Folder 19)
  - Fourth International. American Section (Folder 20)
  - Fourth International. Australian Section (Folder 21)
  - Fourth International. Austrian Section (Folder 22)
  - Fourth International. Belgian Section (Folder 23)
  - Fourth International. British Section (Folder 24)
  - Fourth International. Bulgarian Section (Folder 25)
  - Fourth International. Canadian Section (Folder 26)
  - Fourth International. Chilean Section (Folder 27)
  - Fourth International. Chinese Section (Folder 28)
  - Fourth International. Czechoslovak Section (Folder 29)
  - Fourth International. Dutch Section (Folder 30)
  - Fourth International. French Section (Folder 31)
  - Fourth International. German Section (Folder 32)
  - Fourth International. Greek Section (Folder 33)
  - Fourth International. Hungarian Section (Folder 34)
  - Fourth International. International Secretariat (Folder 35)
  - Fourth International. International Secretariat (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Fourth International. Italian Section (Folder 2)
  - Fourth International. Lithuanian Section (Folder 3)
  - Fourth International. Norwegian Section (Folder 4)
  - Fourth International. Pan American Commission (Folder 5)
  - Fourth International. Polish Section (Folder 6)
  - Fourth International. Russian Section (Folder 7)
  - Fourth International. Spanish Section (Folder 8)
  - Fourth International. Swiss Section (Folder 9)
  - France. Consulat (Istanbul) (Folder 10)
  - Frank, Jakob (Folder 11)
  - Frank, Waldo (Folder 12)
  - Frankel, Jan (Folder 13)
  - Frankfurter, Gerard (Folder 14)
  - Frankfurter, Richard (Folder 15)
  - Frey, Josef (Folder 16)
  - Friedberg, Karl (Folder 17)
  - Friedmann, O. (Folder 18)
  - Frohlich, Ernst (Folder 19)
  - Furtmuller, Lux (Folder 20)
  - Fux, Georges (Folder 21)
  - Galloy, Florent (Folder 22)
  - Garcia Tellez, Ignacio (Folder 23)
  - Garretto, Giordano (Folder 24)
  - Gassin, D. (Folder 25)
  - Gatschev, D. (Folder 26)
  - Gebaide, Jack (Folder 27)
  - Germany. Konsulat (Istanbul) (Folder 28)
  - Geyer, Florian (Folder 29)
  - Gilboy, James A. (Folder 30)
  - Gitlow, Benjamin (Folder 31)
  - Glanz, Aaron (Folder 32)
  - Glass, C. Frank (Folder 33)
  - Glassford, Pelham D. (Folder 34)
  - Glotzer, Albert (Folder 35)
  - Goddard, Morrill (Folder 36)
  - Goldenberg, Boris (Folder 37)
  - Goldman, Albert (Folder 38)
  - Goldstein, Elizabeth (Folder 39)
  - Gollancz, Victor (Folder 40)
  - Goodlatte, C. R. (Folder 41)
  - Gordon, Sam (Folder 42)
  - Gould, Nathan (Folder 43)
  - Grad, Berthold (Folder 44)
  - Grasset (Publishers) (Folder 45)
  - Great Britain. Consulate (Istanbul) (Folder 46)
  - Green, Bernard (Folder 47)
  - Greesha (Folder 48)
  - Grein, M. (Folder 49)
  - Gross, Fritz (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Groves, Reginald (Folder 2)
  - Grylewicz, Anton (Folder 3)
  - Guernot, Henri (Folder 4)
  - Gumpertz (Folder 5)
  - Hamel (Folder 6)
  - Hansen, Emil (Folder 7)
  - Hansen, Joseph (Folder 8)
  - Harper and Brothers (Publishers) (Folder 9)
  - Harte, Jesse S. (Folder 10)
  - Hartmann, Dr. (Folder 11)
  - Hartmann, George Wilford (Folder 12)
  - Heard, Alexander (Folder 13)
  - Heisler, Francis (Folder 14)
  - Heisler, Ivan (Folder 15)
  - Held, Walter (Folder 16)
  - Heller, Otto (Folder 17)
  - Herring, Hubert C. (Folder 18)
  - Hippe, O. (Folder 19)
  - Hogarth Hill, A. (Folder 20)
  - Holm og Rode (Law firm) (Folder 21)
  - Hook, Sidney (Folder 22)
  - Howe, Quincy (Folder 23)
  - Hughes, Emrys (Folder 24)
  - Hurm (Folder 25)
  - Independent Labour Party (Great Britain) (Folder 26)
  - Institut Lenina (Folder 27)
  - Isaacs, Harold R. (Folder 28)
  - Istanbul (Turkey) Prefecture of Police (Folder 29)
  - Istanbul (Turkey) Vali (Folder 30)
  - Istanbul Universitesi (Folder 31)
  - Istrati, Painati (Folder 32)
  - Italy. Consolato (Istanbul) (Folder 33)
  - James, C. L. R. (Folder 34)
  - Jansen, Boris (Folder 35)
  - Jerabek, Ferdinand (Folder 36)
  - Johnsen, Per (Folder 37)
  - Johnson, Chester K. (Folder 38)
  - Johnstone, K. (Folder 39)
  - Joko (Folder 40)
  - Jones, C. R. (Folder 41)
  - Jungclas, Georg (Folder 42)
  - Kadt, Jacques de (Folder 43)
  - Karlin (Folder 44)
  - Karsner, Rose (Folder 45)
  - Kaun, Alexander S. (Folder 46)
  - Ken (Magazine) (Folder 47)
  - Kiar, Elisabeth (Folder 48)
  - Kirchhoff, Paul (Folder 49)
  - Kirchwey, Freda (Folder 50)
  - Kitain, Hyman (Folder 51)
  - Klement, Rudolf (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Kliachko, Anna K. (Folder 2)
  - Kling, Lazar (Folder 3)
  - Kluger, Pearl (Folder 4)
  - Knickerbocker, H. R. (Folder 5)
  - Knorr, Louis C. (Folder 6)
  - Knudsen, Hilda (Folder 7)
  - Knudsen, Hjordis (Folder 8)
  - Knudsen, Konrad (Folder 9)
  - Koffler, Dosio (Folder 10)
  - Kogan, L. (Folder 11)
  - Konikow, Antoinette (Folder 12)
  - Kopp, George (Folder 13)
  - Koston, Paul (Folder 14)
  - Krog, Helge (Folder 15)
  - Kruger (Folder 16)
  - Kurodov, Petr S. (Folder 17)
  - Lacroix, Henri (Folder 18)
  - LaFollette, Suzanne (Folder 19)
  - Lagorce, G. (Folder 20)
  - Lal, Chaman (Folder 21)
  - Landau, Kurt (Folder 22)
  - Lander, William (Folder 23)
  - Lange, C. V. (Folder 24)
  - Langer, William L. (Folder 25)
  - Lanis, Vera (Folder 26)
  - Lankin, Sol (Folder 27)
  - Lansbury, George (Folder 28)
  - Laski, Harold J. (Folder 29)
  - Lawrence, Susan A. (Folder 30)
  - League for Industrial Democracy (U.S.) (Folder 31)
  - Lenero, Agustin (Folder 32)
  - Lenorowicz, H. (Folder 33)
  - Leonetti, Alfonso (Folder 34)
  - Leonhard, Alida (Folder 35)
  - Lerner, Abba P. (Folder 36)
  - Lesoil, Leon (Folder 37)
  - Letsky, W. (Folder 38)
  - Levine (Folder 39)
  - Levine, Isaac Don (Folder 40)
  - Levinson, Fanny (Folder 41)
  - Liberty (Folder 42)
  - Lie, Trygve (Folder 43)
  - Lieber, Maxim (Folder 44)
  - Life (Folder 45)
  - Lobe, Paul (Folder 46)
  - Loduca, J. M. (Folder 47)
  - Loeffler (Folder 48)
  - London, Joan (Folder 49)
  - Longman's (Publishers) (Folder 50)
  - Lore, Ludwig (Folder 51)
  - Lossey, Frank (Folder 52)
  - Ludwig, Emil (Folder 53)
  - Lydenberg, H. M. (Folder 54)
  - Lyons, Eugene (Folder 55)
  - McDonald, Dorothy (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Macdonald, Dwight (Folder 2)
  - MacDonald, James Ramsay (Folder 3)
  - McDonald, John (Folder 4)
  - Maitland, Frank (Folder 5)
  - Majer-Kroupensky (Folder 6)
  - Malamuth, Charles (Folder 7)
  - Malaquais, Jean (Folder 8)
  - Malik Company (Folder 9)
  - Malinvaud, Antoine (Folder 10)
  - Mangan, Sherry (Folder 11)
  - Mann, Klaus (Folder 12)
  - Manov, Stephane (Folder 13)
  - Manulis, Pedro (Folder 14)
  - Margoshes, Samuel (Folder 15)
  - Markstahler, W. (Folder 16)
  - Martin, Jeanne (Folder 17)
  - Marx, Louis (Folder 18)
  - Maslow, Arkadi (Folder 19)
  - Matlow, Bert (Folder 20)
  - Matthews, J. B. (Folder 21)
  - Maule, Harry E. (Folder 22)
  - Mayer, Carl (Folder 23)
  - Mayer, Gustav (Folder 24)
  - Meichler, Jean (Folder 25)
  - Mencken, H. L. (Folder 26)
  - Mendel, Alfred O. (Folder 27)
  - Mexico. Administracion de la Aduana (Folder 28)
  - Mexico. Secretario de Gobernacion (Folder 29)
  - Meyer, Haakon (Folder 30)
  - Miasnikov, Gabriel (Folder 31)
  - Michalec, F. (Folder 32)
  - The Militant (Folder 33)
  - Mill, M. (Folder 34)
  - Miller, Bert (Folder 35)
  - Milton, Harry (Folder 36)
  - Modern Quarterly (Folder 37)
  - Moise, E. (Folder 38)
  - Molinier, Henri (Folder 39)
  - Molinier, Raymond (Folder 40-41)
  - Montagu, Ivor (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Monzie, Anatole de (Folder 2)
  - Mordell, Albert (Folder 3)
  - Morrow, Felix (Folder 4)
  - Moustakis, Chris (Folder 5)
  - Muller, Alexander (Folder 6)
  - Muller, Carl (Folder 7)
  - Muste, A. J. (Folder 8)
  - Nanjo, S. (Folder 9)
  - Narten, Lu (Folder 10)
  - Nathan (Folder 11)
  - The Nation (Folder 12)
  - National Council of Labour Colleges (Great Britain) (Folder 13)
  - National News Agency (Folder 14)
  - Naville, Denise (Folder 15)
  - Naville, Pierre (Folder 16)
  - Nearing, Scott (Folder 17)
  - Neergaard, Joogen (Folder 18)
  - Neue Weltbuhne (Folder 19)
  - Neumann, Margarete Buber (Folder 20)
  - Neumann, Richard (Folder 21)
  - Neurath, Alois (Folder 22)
  - The New International (Folder 23)
  - The New Leader (Folder 24)
  - The New York Times (Folder 25)
  - News Chronicle (London) (Folder 26)
  - Niel-sih (Folder 27)
  - Nielsen, Marie (Folder 28)
  - De Nieuwe Fakkel (Folder 29)
  - Nin, Andres (Folder 30)
  - Norske Creditbank (Folder 31)
  - Norske Studentersamfund (Folder 32)
  - North American Newspaper Alliance (Folder 33)
  - Norway. Centralpasskontoret (Folder 34)
  - Norwegian Telegraph Company (Folder 35)
  - Novack, George (Folder 36)
  - O'Brien, Nora Connolly (Folder 37)
  - L'Oeuvre (Folder 38)
  - Olberg, Valentin (Folder 39)
  - Orbis Verlag (Folder 40)
  - Oreosile (Folder 41)
  - Ost, Walter (Folder 42)
  - Overstraten, van (Folder 43)
  - Palley, B. (Folder 44)
  - Palmer (Folder 45)
  - Parijanine, Maurice (Folder 46)
  - Paris-Soir (Folder 47)
  - Partisan Review (Folder 48)
  - Paton, John (Folder 49)
  - Pawelka, Franz (Folder 50)
  - Paz, Magdeleine (Folder 51)
  - Paz, Maurice (Folder 52)
  - Pecker, I. (Folder 53)
  - Perera, S. (Folder 54)
  - Permanente Revolution (Folder 55)
  - Pero, R. (Folder 56)
  - Perrone, Ottorino (Folder 57)
  - Le Peuple (Folder 58)
  - Pfemfert, Alexandra (Folder 59)
  - Pfemfert, Alexandra (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - Pfemfert, Franz (Folder 4-5)
  - Phillips, William (Folder 6)
  - Pikas (Folder 7)
  - Pizzi de Porras, Enrique (Folder 8)
  - Plisnier, Charles (Folder 9)
  - Plotkin, Abraham (Folder 10)
  - Polk, L. (Folder 11)
  - Pollak, Hans (Folder 12)
  - Porszolt, Ladislaus (Folder 13)
  - Posthumus, N. W. (Folder 14)
  - Presclif, Erwin (Folder 15)
  - Proletaire (Folder 16)
  - Pruette, Lorine (Folder 17)
  - Puntervold, Michael (Folder 18)
  - Purkis, Stewart (Folder 19)
  - R. (Folder 20)
  - Rahv, Philip (Folder 21)
  - Rakovskii, Khristian (Folder 22)
  - Ranc, R. (Folder 23)
  - Ransom, Arthur (Folder 24)
  - Ravazzoli, Paolo (Folder 25)
  - Reese, Maria (Folder 26)
  - Reich, Wilhelm (Folder 27)
  - Reiland (Folder 28)
  - Reiss, Else (Folder 29)
  - Revolution (Folder 30)
  - Rice, Eleanor (Folder 31)
  - Rieder (Folder 32)
  - Riel, R. van (Folder 33)
  - Rivera, Diego (Folder 34)
  - Robertson, Earl (Folder 35)
  - Robinson, Edward G. (Folder 36)
  - Robinson, Gladys L. C. (Folder 37)
  - Robinson, Viola (Folder 38)
  - Rodolf, Frank M. (Folder 39)
  - Rodriguez Revilla, Vincente (Folder 40)
  - Roelandt, Lode (Folder 41)
  - Romeo, Miguel (Folder 42)
  - Rorty, James (Folder 43)
  - Rosenfeld, Kurt (Folder 44)
  - Rosenthal, Georges (Folder 45)
  - Rosenthal, Gerard (Folder 46)
  - Rosmer, Alfred (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Rosmer, Marguerite (Folder 2)
  - Rosovskii, R. (Folder 3)
  - Ross, Edward Alsworth (Folder 4)
  - Rous, Jean (Folder 5)
  - Rubena, Reguis (Folder 6)
  - Rubinstein, Z. H. (Folder 7)
  - Ruhle, Charles C. (Folder 8)
  - Ruhle, Otto (Folder 9)
  - Ruschak, Michael (Folder 10)
  - Ruthe, Margarethe (Folder 11)
  - S. Fischer Verlag (Folder 12)
  - Saavedra, Lucio (Folder 13)
  - Salfrys, S. (Folder 14)
  - Salinger, Paul (Folder 15)
  - Salus, Wolfgang Vaclav (Folder 16)
  - Sapp, Nusse (Folder 17)
  - The Saturday Evening Post (Folder 18)
  - Saul, George J. (Folder 19)
  - Schapiro, Meyer (Folder 20)
  - Scheflo, Olav (Folder 21)
  - Schlamm, Willi (Folder 22)
  - Schmalhausen, Samuel D. (Folder 23)
  - Schmidt, Peter J. (Folder 24)
  - Scholer, Alfred (Folder 25)
  - Schon, Alois (Folder 26)
  - Schultz, Henry (Folder 27)
  - Schumann, Harry (Folder 28)
  - Schurer, Heinz (Folder 29)
  - Schussler, Otto (Folder 30)
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln (Folder 31)
  - Schwind, Marx (Folder 32)
  - Scribner's (Publishers) (Folder 33)
  - Seagel, Ernest (Folder 34)
  - Sedov, Lev (Folder 35-37)
  - Seipold, Oskar (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Semenovna, Lena (Folder 2)
  - Serge, Victor (Folder 3)
  - Shachtman, Max (Folder 4)
  - Simon and Schuster (Publishers) (Folder 5)
  - Sinclair, Upton (Folder 6)
  - Skandera, R. (Folder 7)
  - Skoglund, Carl (Folder 8)
  - Sneevliet, Henk (Folder 9)
  - Snowden, Philip (Folder 10)
  - Sobolevicius, Abraham (Folder 11)
  - Sobolevicius, Roman (Folder 12)
  - Socialist Appeal (Folder 13)
  - Socialist Labour Party (Australia) (Folder 14)
  - Solow, Herbert (Folder 15)
  - Sonnenschein, Hugo (Folder 16)
  - Sosnovskaia (Folder 17)
  - Souvarine, Boris (Folder 18)
  - Soviet Union. Konsul'stvo (Istanbul) (Folder 19)
  - Spaak, Paul (Folder 20)
  - Spanjer, Bep (Folder 21)
  - Spark (Folder 22)
  - Spector, Maurice (Folder 23)
  - Stanley, Sherman (Folder 24)
  - Stein, A. (Folder 25)
  - Steinbauer (Folder 26)
  - Sterling, Max (Folder 27)
  - Sternberg, Fritz (Folder 28)
  - Stewart, George (Folder 29)
  - Stewart, James B. (Folder 30)
  - Stift, Leopold (Folder 31)
  - Stoi (Folder 32)
  - Stolberg, Benjamin (Folder 33)
  - Stoylen, Andreas (Folder 34)
  - Strasser, I. (Folder 35)
  - Strobel, Erwin (Folder 36)
  - Sturm, Fritz (Folder 37)
  - Sumner, Charles (Folder 38)
  - Sveen, Reidar (Folder 39)
  - Swabeck, Arne (Folder 40)
  - Tarov, Arven (Folder 41)
  - Thibedi, T. (Folder 42)
  - Thomas (Folder 43)
  - Thomas, Wendelin (Folder 44)
  - Toller, Ernst (Folder 45)
  - Treint, Albert (Folder 46)
  - Tresca, Carlo (Folder 47)
  - Tresso, Pietro (Folder 48)
  - Treves Editori (Folder 49)
  - Tsion, B. (Folder 50)
  - Turkey. Dahiliye Vekaleti (Folder 51)
  - Turkey. Hariciye Vekaleti (Folder 52)
  - Tyden Norsk Forlag (Folder 53)
  - Unidentified (Folder 54)
  - United Press International (Folder 55)
  - United States. Consulate (Istanbul) (Folder 56)
  - Unzer Kamf (Folder 57)
  - Urbahns, Hugo (Folder 58)
  - Vallon, Joseph (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Van Heijenoort, Jean (Folder 2)
  - Vela, Marino (Folder 3)
  - Vereecken, Georges (Folder 4)
  - La Verite (Folder 5)
  - Villareal, Antonio I. (Folder 6)
  - Villasenor, Eduardo (Folder 7)
  - Villasenor, Victor Manuel (Folder 8)
  - Vitte (Folder 9)
  - Voinoff, Floro D. (Folder 10)
  - La Voix Communiste (Folder 11)
  - Volkov, V. T. (Folder 12)
  - Volkova, Zinaida (Folder 13)
  - Vsesoiuznaia Kommunisticheskaia Partiia (bol'shevikov) (Folder 14)
  - Walcher, Jakob (Folder 15)
  - Walker, Charles R. (Folder 16)
  - Walsh, F. P. (Folder 17)
  - Wasserman, Jac (Folder 18)
  - Webb, Beatrice (Folder 19)
  - Webb, Sidney (Folder 20)
  - Weber, Jack (Folder 21)
  - Weber, Sara (Folder 22)
  - Wechsler, Abraham (Folder 23)
  - Wegener, Franz (Folder 24)
  - Weinberg, Bruno (Folder 25)
  - Weisbord, Albert (Folder 26)
  - Weiss (Folder 27)
  - Wells, Marjorie (Folder 28)
  - Westermann, A. (Folder 29)
  - Weston, Harold (Folder 30)
  - White, Leslie (Folder 31)
  - Whitten, Ralph B. (Folder 32)
  - Widick, B. J. (Folder 33)
  - Wilde, M. (Folder 34)
  - Wilfert, Hans (Folder 35)
  - Wilkinson, E. C. (Folder 36)
  - Wolf, Erwin (Folder 37)
  - Wolfe, Bernard (Folder 38)
  - Wollenberg, Erich (Folder 39)
  - Workers' News (Folder 40)
  - Worrall, R. S. (Folder 41)
  - Wright, John G. (Folder 42)
  - Wullens, Maurice (Folder 43)
  - Young, Cyrus (Folder 44)
  - Zack, Joseph (Folder 45)
  - Zeller, Fred (Folder 46)
- PHONORECORDS, 1938. (Record cabinet)
  Sound recordings of a speech by Leon Trotsky.
  - Two phonorecord disks of a sound recorded speech (in English) by Leon Trotsky on the anniversaries of the Fourth International and of the Socialist Workers Party, Coyoacan, 1938 October 10. See also LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Sound recorded speech (1938 October 10); and PHONOTAPE (Record-cabinet Record cabinet)
- PHONOTAPE, 1938. (Cassette cabinet)
  Copy of sound recordings of a speech by Leon Trotsky.
  - Phonotape cassette of a sound recorded speech (in English) by Leon Trotsky on the anniversaries of the Fourth International and of the Socialist Workers Party, Coyoacan, 1938 October 10. Copy made from phonorecord disks. See also LEON TROTSKY SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Sound recorded speech (1938 October 10); and PHONORECORDS (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1940. (Photo file)
  - 8 prints of Leon Trotsky and his wife, Natalia Sedova Trotskaia, In Mexico. Prints autographed by Trotskaia, undated (Envelope A)
  - 15 prints of Evelyn Reed and guards and other members of the Trotsky household at the villa of Leon Trotsky in Coyoacan, Mexico, 1940 (Envelope B)
  - 25 prints of the villa of Leon Trotsky in Coyo9acan, Mexico, showing fortification and other security measures, 1940 (Envelope C)
  - 1 print, incompletely identified, take on the ocean liner "Normandie", possibly of Ramon Mercader, undated (Envelope D)
- ADDENDUM, 1920-1995 (Box 46-47, art rack)
  The Addendum includes United States government documents detailing surveillance of Leon Trotsky in exile (photocopies obtained from government archives); bibliographies of writings by Trotsky and of internal bulletins of the Fourth International movement during his lifetime; and a subject file of assorted correspondence, memoranda and printed matter relating to Trotsky and Trotskyism. Also included is a portrait painting of Natalia Sedova Trotsky.
  - U.S. Government Surveillance File, 1920-1976 (Box 46)
    U.S. Department of State dispatches and lists of U.S. government documents relating to Leon Trotsky and Trotskyists.
    - Lists of documents, 1929-1976
      - U.S. Department of State list of dispatches regarding Leon Trotsky, with summaries of contents, 1929-1941 (Box-folder 46: 1)
      - U.S. Department of State list of dispatches regarding arrest of Charles Orr in Spain, with summaries of contents, 1937. (Box-folder 46: 2)
        Summaries also refer to arrests of Hugo Oehler and Wolf Kupinsky in Spain.
      - List of U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation reports, memoranda and letters relating to Leon Trotsky and Trotskyists, 1936-1976 (Box-folder 46: 3)
    - U.S. Department of State documents, 1920-1944
      - 1920. Dispatches from Norway relating to William Morris Konikov (Box-folder 46: 4)
      - 1932. Dispatch and memorandum from Great Britain, relating to Communist Left Opposition in the United States (Box-folder 46: 5)
      - 1936. Dispatches from Belgium relating to involvement of Communist Left Opposition with radical activities in Belgium (Box-folder 46: 6)
      - 1937. Dispatch from Mexico relating to the American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky (Box-folder 46: 8)
      - 1938. Dispatch from Mexico relating to Russell Blackwell. Includes affidavit by Trotsky (Box-folder 46: 8)
      - 1939. Dispatch from Belgium relating to Trotskyists in the United States. Includes U.S. Office of Naval Intelligence memorandum on same subject (Box-folder 46: 9)
      - 1940. Dispatches from Mexico relating to attack on Trotsky compound and murder of Robert Sheldon Harte, shipment of Trotsky archives to Harvard University, and assassination of Trotsky (Box-folder 46: 10)
      - 1943. Dispatches from Mexico relating to local reaction to dissolution of Communist International (Box-folder 46: 11)
      - 1944. Dispatch from Mexico relating to suppression of Mexican Trotskyists (Box-folder 46: 12)
    - Miscellany. Notes and material on organization of U.S. government records (Box-folder 46: 13)
  - Bibliographic File, 1967-1981. (Box 46)
    Bibliographies of writings by Leon Trotsky and of early Fourth International internal bulletins.
    - “Articles by Leon Trotsky in The Militant, 1929-1941, and The New and Fourth International, 1934-1956” (Education for Socialists bulletin), 1967 (Box-folder 46: 14)
    - Louis Sinclair, “Documents and Discussions, 1930-1940: Source Material for the History of the 4th International.” Typescript, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 15)
    - “English Language Bulletins of the 1930s: A List and Tables of Contents” (drawn from Sinclair bibliography above). Typescript, 1981 (Box-folder 46: 16)
    - “Fourth International Bulletins and Other Ephemera, 1930-1940, in English, French, German, Spanish and Dutch.” Typescript guide to microfilm holdings, undated (Box-folder 46: 17)
  - Subject File II, 1933-1995. (Box 47)
    Correspondence, memoranda, notes and printed matter relating to Leon Trotsky and Trotskyism.
    - General, 1933-1989.
      Memoirs and other articles about Trotsky and Trotskyism in general. Printed unless otherwise stated
      - Bongiovanni, Bruno, “The Dissolution of Trotskyism,” Telos, 1982 Summer (Box-folder 47: 1)
      - Dunayevskaya, Raya, “Leon Trotsky as Man and Theoretician,” Studies in Comparative Communism, 1977 Spring/Summer. (Box-folder 47: 2)
        Includes “Comment” by Ernest Mandel